<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<project>
	<PreviewIconFile>preview_icon.png</PreviewIconFile>
	<ItemDescriptionShort>Gyll’s Vanilla: Heroes redesigns or rebalances all 15 original hero classes</ItemDescriptionShort>
	<ModDataPath>C:/Program Files (x86)/Darkest Dungeon/mods/gylls_vanilla_heroes/</ModDataPath>
	<Title>Gyll&apos;s Vanilla: Heroes</Title>
	<Language>english</Language>
	<UpdateDetails/>
	<Visibility>public</Visibility>
	<UploadMode>copy_and_upload</UploadMode>
	<VersionMajor>0</VersionMajor>
	<VersionMinor>0</VersionMinor>
	<TargetBuild>21142</TargetBuild>
	<Tags>
		<Tags>Class Tweaks</Tags>
	</Tags>
	<ItemDescription>[b]Gyll’s Vanilla: Heroes[/b] redesigns or rebalances all 15 original hero classes. [i]Flagellant &amp; Shieldbreaker redesigns are in the works and will be released as separate mods when ready.[/i]

[h1]About Gyll’s Vanilla[/h1]
[b]Gyll’s Vanilla[/b] is a collection of mods for Darkest Dungeon, each of which redesigns a single aspect of the game. These mods are balanced against the vanilla base game and designed for maximum compatibility, creating a solid foundation for your modded campaigns. [i]Heroes is currently the only mod in the series. Quirks and Monsters are planned as the next two.[/i]

[h1]Design Goals[/h1]
- Increase the number of viable playstyles for each class
- Ensure that no class is consistently outshined by any other
- Deliver mechanically on the promise of the original art &amp; character designs
- In general, simplify skills &amp; tooltips
- Ensure that remaining effects are impactful, both in terms of feel and in how they affect your decisions

[h1]Design Principles[/h1]
[b]Guild Description[/b]: The guild description was respected as the hero’s “blueprint”. These have not been changed, and still apply to the modded version of the hero in all cases.

[b]Minimal Lost Utility[/b]: Strategies that were effective in the base game should not be rendered useless or unplayable, only the most powerful have been slightly reduced in effectiveness. The exception to this rule is “boss cheese” strategies such as Rallying Flare vs the Swine Prince.

[b]Trinket Usage[/b]: This mod does not change trinkets, so heroes must still make effective use of all of their unmodded trinkets.

[h1]Changelog[/h1]
[url=https://docs.google.com/document/d/1kAKu8KbA2GDYOJW7PDzXmhXI0PVUxgA-Uw3jJ90QGhY/edit?usp=sharing]Click to read the full changelog[/url]

[h1]Compatibility[/h1]
This mod uses the .art and .info files for the heroes it modifies, as well as the base camping skills file. If another mod uses these files, there will be conflicts. Also, full overhauls such as Pitch Black Dungeon that rely on changes being made to every hero will have severe balance issues if used with this mod. If your mod doesn’t fall into either of these categories then congratulations, it’s compatible!

[h1]Localization[/h1]
Some minimal effort has been expended to make the mod playable in non-English languages, however only English has been thoroughly tested, and in other languages you will encounter a few English strings and possibly some very long/cut off tooltips. Please contact me if you are willing to translate this mod into another language!

[h1]Contact[/h1]
If you’d like to provide translations, hire me to design heroes for your game, or yell at me for ruining your life with my free mod; please post a comment here, add me on discord at Gyll#0788, or email me at gyllgaming@gmail.com. Bug reports and balance feedback are also welcome!

[h1]Thanks[/h1]
Thanks to Clair de Lune, Chogex, O’Nightmare!, and Tilted Hat for helping me with questions in the Moonlit Dungeon Discord. Thanks to Red Hook Studios for making such a great &amp; moddable game!

[h1]Disclaimer[/h1]
[i]Gyll’s Vanilla: Heroes is not an official Red Hook Studios product or product modification, and Red Hook Studios Inc. is not responsible in any way for changes or damages that may result from using the mod. Furthermore, “Darkest Dungeon” and the Darkest Dungeon logo are trademarks of Red Hook Studios Inc. All content in the game is Copyright Red Hook Studios Inc. All rights reserved.[/i]

[h1]Known Issues[/h1]
If you enable this mod while in a dungeon with a Houndmaster, his new transforms will not work properly and you will have access to all of his skills at once, and be able to spam his human skills without ever ending your turn. Leave the dungeon, or finish it before enabling this mod to avoid this bug!
</ItemDescription>
	<PublishedFileId>1385283735</PublishedFileId>
</project>

